Michael Schenck <u>mdschenck@gmail.com</u> <u>https://linkedin.com/in/michaeldschenck</u> (404)-450-5326

### Summary:

Extensive experience leading teams and developing solutions to complex logistical challenges. Solutions based fulfillment systems integration, with a keen understanding of the interplay between customer facing and back end operations. Full Stack Flex web development.

I aim to further my development in the Ecommerce sphere working in the Magento 2 platform for a national company with room for advancement and growth.

# Experience:

# 2020-Present

Digital Merchandising / UI & Ecommerce Fulfillment, Gourmet Foods International (Atlanta, GA). Maintained daily merchandising and user interface of ecommerce specialty food website <a href="www.gourmetdash.com">www.gourmetdash.com</a> with over 50k monthly visitors. Responsible for the set up and execution of timed event promotions, pricing, product listings and management of all digital assets for the main site as well as multiple mirror sites set up for national retail partners. In 2022, completed rebranding and launch of a new Magento 2 based platform for the B2C ecommerce site. Assisted with complete company wide taxonomy and category assignment in preparation for new site launch. Managed third party fulfillment systems for multiple national ecommerce food distributors including Murray's Cheese (B2C) and US Foods (B2B). Helped lead the new ecommerce department at Gourmet Foods International to 400% growth in revenue over 2 years. Magento 2 admin & merchandising.

#### 2016 - 2020

Founder, C.O.O. of BAG'd (Atlanta,GA). Founded a direct to consumer online grocery and wellness delivery service. Duties include sourcing all products and maintaining all vendor relationships, customer service, marketing including social media, accounting, and operations. Designed and deployed WIX platform ecommerce website and maintained all content, digital assets and product listings.

### 2008 - 2020

Founder, C.O.O. The Turnip Truck of Georgia, LLC (Atlanta, GA). Founded a boutique produce and specialty foodservice delivery company with an emphasis on providing professional distribution services to local farmers and the highest quality products to Atlanta area restaurants. Duties Including: Procurement / purchasing and pricing, daily reconciliation and accounting. Advertising and promotions including social media marketing, weekly price list and market report publication. Managed all sales and operations on average yearly revenue of 1.5m. over 12 years. In 2015 supervised launch of

Magento 1 platform ecommerce website, including site wireframe and design, full product taxonomy and category hierarchy. Managed all web content, digital assets and product listings. Magento 1 admin from 2015-2020.

# Education:

Full Stack Flex Web Development Certificate Georgia Institute of Technology (Atlanta, GA)

Food service Management, Culinary Arts Greenville Technical College (Greenville, SC)

# Job Related Skills:

Website Design & Administration Ecommerce Fulfillment Systems Management / Supervision Purchasing & Inventory Management Logistics / Shipping Spanish Language Proficiency

# **Technical Skills:**

Html, Css, Wireframe & Site Design
Bootstrap, Materialize Frameworks
JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js
MySQL, API calls & integrations
GitHub / Version Control
Magento 2 Pagebuilder Design
Magento 2 Configuration & Plugin Modules
Shipstation & Shipper HQ Fulfillment Platforms